<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog>
    <book id="1">
        <title>Oven Baked Fries</title>
        <!--image>https://recipedo.nodeda.com/gallery/ovenbakedfries.jpg</image-->
        <image>https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1a10cb_9e51ae605cbb4f0cb91b09dfa3b54185~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_640,h_402,al_c,q_80,enc_auto/Image-empty-state.jpg</image>
        <prep>20-25 Minutes</prep>
        <cook>10-14 Minutes</cook>
        <level>Intermediate</level>
        <Servings>12 Cookies</Servings>
        <rating>1</rating>
        <about>This recipe is for a classic chocolate chunk cookie made with all-purpose flour, baking soda, salt, butter, white and brown sugar, eggs, vanilla extract, and chocolate chunks or chips. The cookies are easy to make and take about 20-25 minutes to prepare. They are baked for 10-12 minutes until the edges are golden brown. The perfect treat to enjoy with a glass of milk or a cup of coffee.</about>
        <ingredients>2 and 1/4 cups of all-purpose flour</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 tsp baking soda</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 tsp salt</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 cup unsalted butter, at room temperature</ingredients>
        <ingredients>3/4 cup white sugar</ingredients>
        <ingredients>3/4 cup brown sugar</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 large eggs</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 tsp vanilla extract</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 cups chocolate chunks or chips</ingredients>
        <directions>Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper.
            In a medium bowl, mix together the flour, baking soda, and salt.
            In a large mixing bowl, cream the butter, white sugar, and brown sugar until smooth. Add the eggs one at a time, mixing well after each addition. Stir in the vanilla extract.
            Gradually add the flour mixture to the butter mixture and mix until just combined. Fold in the chocolate chunks or chips.
            Using a cookie scoop or spoon, drop rounded balls of dough onto the prepared baking sheet.
            Bake for 10-12 minutes, or until the edges are golden brown. Allow cookies to cool on the baking sheet for 5 minutes before transferring them to a wire rack to cool completely.

            Enjoy your homemade chocolate chunk cookies!</directions>
    </book>

   
</catalog>
