<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog>
    <book id="1">
        <title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
        <!--image>https://recipedo.nodeda.com/gallery/ovenbakedfries.jpg</image-->
        <image>https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1a10cb_9e51ae605cbb4f0cb91b09dfa3b54185~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_640,h_402,al_c,q_80,enc_auto/Image-empty-state.jpg</image>
        <prep>20-25 Minutes</prep>
        <cook>10-14 Minutes</cook>
        <level>Intermediate</level>
        <Servings>12 Cookies</Servings>
        <rating>1</rating>
        <about>This recipe is for a classic chocolate chunk cookie made with all-purpose flour, baking soda, salt, butter, white and brown sugar, eggs, vanilla extract, and chocolate chunks or chips. The cookies are easy to make and take about 20-25 minutes to prepare. They are baked for 10-12 minutes until the edges are golden brown. The perfect treat to enjoy with a glass of milk or a cup of coffee.</about>
        <ingredients>2 and 1/4 cups of all-purpose flour</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 tsp baking soda</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 tsp salt</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 cup unsalted butter, at room temperature</ingredients>
        <ingredients>3/4 cup white sugar</ingredients>
        <ingredients>3/4 cup brown sugar</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 large eggs</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 tsp vanilla extract</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 cups chocolate chunks or chips</ingredients>
        <directions>Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Line a baking sheet with parchment paper.
            In a medium bowl, mix together the flour, baking soda, and salt.
            In a large mixing bowl, cream the butter, white sugar, and brown sugar until smooth. Add the eggs one at a time, mixing well after each addition. Stir in the vanilla extract.
            Gradually add the flour mixture to the butter mixture and mix until just combined. Fold in the chocolate chunks or chips.
            Using a cookie scoop or spoon, drop rounded balls of dough onto the prepared baking sheet.
            Bake for 10-12 minutes, or until the edges are golden brown. Allow cookies to cool on the baking sheet for 5 minutes before transferring them to a wire rack to cool completely.

            Enjoy your homemade chocolate chunk cookies!</directions>
    </book>
    <book id="2">
        <title>Corned Beef and Cabbage</title>
        <!--image>https://recipedo.nodeda.com/gallery/ovenbakedfries.jpg</image-->
        <image>https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1a10cb_f5b9950c60bc4331b4f1327f1fcf5fae~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_650,h_408,al_c,q_80,enc_auto/Image-empty-state.jpg</image>
        <prep>15-20 Minutes</prep>
        <cook>3-3.5 hours</cook>
        <level>Intermediate</level>
        <Servings>6-8</Servings>
        <rating>1</rating>
        <about>This traditional Irish dish is perfect for St. Patrick's Day or any other day. Corned beef is cooked in a flavorful broth with cabbage, potatoes, and carrots. This dish is hearty and delicious; the leftovers are great for sandwiches.</about>
        <ingredients>4-5 lb corned beef brisket</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 large onion, peeled and quartered</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 cloves garlic, peeled</ingredients>
        <ingredients>4 cups beef broth</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 cup water</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup brown sugar</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup honey</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 tbsp pickling spice</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 bay leaves</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 head of green cabbage, cut into wedges</ingredients>
        <ingredients>4-6 small red potatoes, quartered</ingredients>
        <ingredients>4-6 carrots, cut into chunks</ingredients>
        <directions>Rinse the corned beef brisket under cold running water and pat dry. Place the brisket in a large Dutch oven or pot.
            Add the onion, garlic, beef broth, water, brown sugar, honey, pickling spice, and bay leaves to the pot. Bring the mixture to a boil, then reduce the heat and simmer for 2-3 hours or until the meat is tender.
            Add the cabbage, potatoes, and carrots to the pot. Bring the mixture to a boil, then reduce the heat and simmer for 30-40 minutes or until the vegetables are tender.
            Remove the brisket from the pot and let it rest for 10-15 minutes before slicing it against the grain.
            Serve the corned beef and vegetables with the cooking liquid as a flavorful broth.</directions>
    </book>
    <book id="3">
        <title>Meatloaf</title>
        <!--image>https://recipedo.nodeda.com/gallery/ovenbakedfries.jpg</image-->
        <image>https://static.wixstatic.com/media/1a10cb_f5b9950c60bc4331b4f1327f1fcf5fae~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_650,h_408,al_c,q_80,enc_auto/Image-empty-state.jpg</image>
        <prep>15-20 Minutes</prep>
        <cook>1 Hour</cook>
        <level>Beginner</level>
        <Servings>4-6</Servings>
        <rating>1</rating>
        <about>This recipe for classic meatloaf is easy to make and packed with flavor. The grated vegetables add moisture to the meatloaf and the ketchup glaze gives it a delicious sweet and tangy finish. This dish is perfect for dinner, and it's also great for meal prepping.</about>
        <ingredients>1 lb ground beef</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/2 cup breadcrumbs</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup milk</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/2 cup grated onion</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup grated carrot</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup grated celery</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 egg</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 tsp salt</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/4 tsp black pepper</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1/4 cup ketchup</ingredients>
        <ingredients>2 tbsp brown sugar</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 tbsp mustard</ingredients>
        <ingredients>1 tsp Worcestershire sauce</ingredients>
        <directions>Preheat the oven to 350 degrees F (175 degrees C). Grease a 9x5 inch loaf pan with cooking spray.
            In a large mixing bowl, combine the ground beef, breadcrumbs, milk, grated onion, grated carrot, grated celery, egg, salt, and pepper. Mix well.
            Press the mixture into the prepared loaf pan.
            In a small bowl, mix together the ketchup, brown sugar, mustard, and Worcestershire sauce. Spread the mixture over the meatloaf.
            Bake for 1 hour, or until the internal temperature reaches 160 degrees F (70 degrees C) on an instant-read thermometer.
            Let the meatloaf rest for 10 minutes before slicing and serving.</directions>
    </book>
</catalog>
